Guide to the Harold Caparn collection, [ca. 1880s-1990s]
Caparn, Harold collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harold Caparn collection, [ca. 1880s-1990s]
8473
Chamberlain, Oliver,
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, postcards, and publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of correspondence, photographs, and plans produced and collected by Harold Caparn. Also includes secondary materials relating and materials related to other members of the Caparn-Chamberlain family who were involved in horticulture, landscape design, and the arts, such as William John Caparne, Thomas John Caparn, and Rhys Caparn.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harold Caparn was a landscape architect who was active in New York during the first four decades of of the twentieth century. He was born in Newark-on-Trent, Nottinghamshire, England and was educated at the University of London and at the Ecole des Beaux-Arts. After arriving in the United States in September, 1889, he worked first in Pittsburgh (1890-1897) and then, beginning in 1899, in New York. He consulted for the New York Zoological Park in the Bronx and designed parts of the landscape and Great Steps of the Bronx Zoo. He was among the first to teach landscape architecture at Columbia University, where he taught from 1911-1913. In 1912, he became the consulting landscape architect for the Brooklyn Botanic Garden, working there for over thirty-two years and designing many areas of the site, including the Cranford Rose Garden, the Magnolia Plaza, the Osborne Garden, the Herb Garden, the Horticultural Section, and the Systematic Section (now called the Plant Family Collection). He also designed parks in Yonkers, Newark, and Manhattan, park-like spaces such as the Woodland Garden at the 1939 World's Fair and Lake View Cemetery in Ithaca, New York, as well as landscape designs for private estates. He was elected a fellow of the American Society of Landscape Architects in 1905 and was elected president in 1912.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of correspondence, photographs, and plans produced and collected by Harold Caparn. Also includes secondary materials relating to Harold Caparn such as photographs, postcards, and publications. In addition, the collection includes materials related to other members of the Caparn-Chamberlain family who were involved in horticulture, landscape design, and the arts, such as William John Caparne, Thomas John Caparn, and Rhys Caparn.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Chamberlain, Oliver,; Caparn, Harold A. (Harold ap Rhys), 1864-1945.; Caparn, Rhys, 1909-1997.; Caparn, Thomas John.; Caparne, William John, 1856-1940.
Subjects:
Landscape architects -- United States.; Landscape architecture -- United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See related collections: William John Caparne painting, #8480, Thomas John Caparn watercolors, #8481, and Rhys Caparn drawings, #8482, in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Harold Caparn
Box 1
Family Photographs
Education and Career
Letters to Newspapers
Notes and Correspondence
Clients
Photographs of Work
Music Related
Secondary Materials
Series II. Rhys Caparn
Box 1
Biographical Materials
Exhibition Catalogs
Printed Material
Series III. Other Caparn Family Members
Box 2
William H. Caparn
Thomas John Caparn
Mary and Ann Caparn
Arthur Caparn
Oliver Chamberlain Jr.
Oliver Chamberlain Sr.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Harold Caparn
  - Family Photographs
    - David Eugene English (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Harold’s brother-in-law
    - Margaret Jane (Caparn) English (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Harold's sister
    - Ann Elizabeth (Price) Caparn (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Harold's mother
    - Harold A. Caparn, 1889-1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Harold A. Caparn, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 89)
      Associated Press Photo.
    - Assorted Caparn Family (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Education and Career
    - Letter of Appointment to H.A. Caparn for Instruction at Columbia University., April 3, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Appointment as Lecturer in Landscape Architecture from Columbia University, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Consultation Hours for Summer Session, 1911, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Harold A. Caparn's Obituary from the New York Times and the New York Harold Tribune, September 25, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Original and copies
    - American Planning and Civic Association passage of a resolution of sorrow, February 5, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Newspapers
    - Letters in the New York Times "In Defense of the Bushes" (copy) and "The Artist and the Artisan" (copy) (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Oiginal publication dates March 26, 1899 and January, 28, 1902
    - Letter in the New York Times - "WHY NEW YORK IS UGLY" from August 2, 1904 (copy) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letter in the New York Times - "High Bridge" from December 7, 1916 (copy) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letter to Mayor LaGuardia, October 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Regarding the problem of smoke pollution in New York City. Response is written by Stanley Howe, the Secretary to the Mayor
    - Letter in the New York Harold-Tribune - "Germ of Big Business", October 20, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Regarding unions and New Deal Labor policy
    - Letter in the New York Harold-Tribune - "Willkie, Then Dewey", March 4, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letter in the New York Harold - Tribune - " To Protect the Parks", June 28, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Regarding Park Commissioner Robert Moses' findings of youth vandalism of parks.
    - Material related to Jackson Hole Monument, June-July 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letter in the New York Harold-Tribune - "Scientific Approach Needed", September 13, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Regarding the "Advertising Council's campaign against venereal diseases.
    - Letter in the New York Harold-Tribune - "Would Hang Ringleaders", September 1944 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letter printed in the New York Herold-Tribune, January 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Regarding smoke pollution. Also includes a copy of the letter sent to Mayor LaGuardia.
  - Notes and Correspondence
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Contents in Greek, French, and English
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - F.D. Coster letter from Bard and Calkins, November 22, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Regarding work Harold had done for him. Contents of the folder also includes background material on F.D. Coster who was later part of the McKesson and Robbins scandal.
    - Correspondence with Carter Glass of the American Planning and Civic Association, February 1943 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Regarding appropriation for the National Resources Planning Board
    - Correspondence with Cleveland Rogers of the City Planning Commission, February 1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Regarding utilization of empty skyscrapers
    - Correspondence with Harvey Wiley Corbett and Ralph Courtney, February 1943 and June 1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Manhattan as Garden City and free trade.
    - Correspondence between George Yarwood and Johannes Steel on June 14, 1977 (copy), March 2010 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence between George Yarwood and Rhy. Caparn Steel, June-July 1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Regarding Harold Caparn. Includes biographical information about Harold Caparn.
  - Clients
    - Harold Caparn's Client List - originals, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Original. The extant client list is from #488 to #667. Items of note of regional interest are listed. Only 3 pages.
    - Plans for National Soldiers Home in Johnson City, Tennessee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Photo.
    - Plan for the Grounds of D.A. Bullard in Schuylerville, New York, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Photo and handwritten legend
    - Plan for the Grounds of Hon. Joseph E. Willard in Fairfax, Virginia, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Eaton Family Residence/ Jewish Center of Norwich., April 15, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Approved Application of National Register of Historic Places. Form and photographs; Eaton Robert
    - Plan - Brooklyn Botanic Garden Systematic Section. 1928., undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Photocopy. General Plan of the Brooklyn Botanic Garden.
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden., September 1937 - November 1937 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Correspondence between Alfred Gunderson and H.A. Caparn regarding Evergreens. Handwritten notes.
    - Plan - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, November 17, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Colored drawing of proposed expansion of plant species in Botanic Garden.
    - Correspondence - Brooklyn Botanic Garden., March 23, 1939 - March 24, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Correspondence between Alfred Gundersen and H.A. Caparn regarding Cypress Family.
    - "Spring Flowers at the Botanic Garden", 1945 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "Landscape Architects Who Have Designed Gardens for Some of Our Great Country Estates" from Country Life in America 38, p. 49, June 1920 (Box 1, Folder 88)
      H.A. Caparn featured in an article with Frederick Law Olmsted, James L. Greenleaf, Ferruccio Vitale, Charles Welford Leavitt, Jr, Albert D. Taylor, Arthur R. Nichols and George Kessler.
    - Easton Estate. Design Home of R.D. Easton in Norwich, New York, c. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Historic Sheffield Commission - Nitrate Village #1, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cayuga Heights, Ithaca Notes (copies), c. 1920s (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Denison Park, Corning New York (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - J.C. Willever estate in Millburn, New Jersey, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Early Site Planning Photos of Denison Park in Corning, New York., Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Photographs of Work
    - Fountain, Milford Park, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Cemetery, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Photos of pond with willow. Photo of mausoleum.
    - Columbus Park, Yonkers, New York, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Grant Park in Yonkers, New York, c. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - J.H. Tanner Home in Ithaca, New York, c. 1915 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Landscape work on Maitland F. Griggs estate in Ardsley, New York, c. 1910-1925 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Includes advertisement for book.
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. Sanatorium in Mt. McGregor, New York, c. 1913-1930 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Sanatorium buildings and grounds. Refectory on right, then infirmary, then ward building
    - Briarcliff Mansion, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Photographs include Landscape Architecture, Interior and Daughters.
    - W.J. Tully Estate in Locust, New York, c. 1918-1921 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Photographs include home, landscaping, entrance, and rose garden.
    - Masonic Home in Utica, New York., Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Original Postcard. Administration Building and Chapel. Client List 617
    - Brooklyn College, July 16, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      East Quad facing watchtower.
    - Magazine and Photograph - "The Orchards" in South Hampton, New York, Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Built 1896. Architects McKim Mead and White. LA Olmstead Bro.
    - Brooklyn Botanical Garden, 1925-1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Photographs include various shots, Japanese garden, plan of development of North Addition, Armillary Sphere, "Cherry Walk", rose garden, plan for rose garden, sculpture "Roses of Yesterday", systematic section, sketch of bridge, landscape, children's garden, Jenkins Fountain and land bath.
    - 156 Fifth Avenue in New York, New York, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Strohmeyer in Newark, New Jersey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Unidentified Photographs of H.A. Caparn Projects, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Music Related
    - Correspondence with conductors and music critics, 1935-1942 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Handwritten Manuscript on Music, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Secondary Materials
    - Roses, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      H. Horace McFarland Com. Harrisburg, PA
    - Photographs - Rhys and Clara Caparn, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      Also one with Anne Elizabeth Caparn. ex Hubbard Collection.
    - Photograph - Clara Howard Jones Royall Caparn with Rhys, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      ex Hubbard Collection.
    - Photograph - George Clarborne Royall, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      2 3/4 years old. ex. Hubbard Collection
    - Photographs - Sarah H. Bishop; Mourning Necklace and Locket; Open Locket Showing Photo, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      Photocopies. Sarah H. Bishop. William H. Caparn. John F. Bishop (deceased husband of Sarah Caparn Bishop)
    - Photograph - Photograph of drawing signed by H.A. Caparn, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      Scene in Wyoming, NJ
    - Photographs - Sarah Horner Caparn Bishop, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      Portrait and Landscape 3 slighty enlarged and 1 normal size.
    - Photographs - Sarah (Birkett) Gilstrap Caparn, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
      2nd wife Willam Horner Caparn. 2 different photos.
    - Photographs - Cemetery in need of Landscaping, undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
      Woodlawn Cemetery NYC. Ex Hubbard Collection; Different views of cemetery scenes; Photo used in article with his drawing showing effect of foliage.
    - Photograph - Rhys by Oliver Chamberlain, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      Backyard sculptor garden.
    - Review - "State Parks" by Harold A. Caparn, November 1921 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      Original. National Municipal Review. Volume X, No. 11. For Rhys Caparn from Harriet Adams (1956)
    - Plans - Design Sketches by Harold Caparn, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
      Sketches of seat, Central Park, fountain and Columbia University. Includes application for American Society of Landscape Architects. Waldo Hutchinson Bench.
    - Correspondence - Cold Spring Harbor (copies), 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
      Village One. Nirate Plant plans, Sheffield, Alabama. Chamberlain Landscapes and writings. 323 ff. 23 photographs.
    - Document - Nomination for National Register of Historic Places, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      Nitrate Village No. 1 Historic District. United States Department of the Interior National Park Services.
    - Correspondence - New York World's Fair, 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
      To Harold A. Caparn from Rhys. New York Times Article "Advance Plan of World's Fair Held 'Defeatist' "
    - Book - The Horticultural Exhibition Gardens on Parade "At the New York World's Fair 1939" Woodland Garden., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      Souvenir Book. Photocopies of New York Times Articles: "A Restful Woodland Garden Created for the World's Fair" (1940) and "Use of Water at World's Fair Holds Hints for Gardeners" (1939)
    - "Glacial Boulders in Gardens" by Harold Caparn, March 9, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 62)
      2 originals. Written at age 79.
    - Correspondence - Memorial letter from National Roadside Council., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      Letter to Rhys from Executive Committee about Harold A. Caparns contributions to Council upon discovery of his death. Minutes and envelope attached.
    - "Art out-of-Doors", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      American Gardens 1890-1930. A Selected Bibliography. The Hunt Botanical Library. and Gardens.
    - "Touring the Brooklyn College Landscape" (copy), 1938, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      "A Guide to the Shrubs and Trees on the Brooklyn College Campus". By Maurice Volaski, '87 and Dr. Roy E. McGowan as Faculty Advisor.
- Series II. Rhys Caparn
  - Biographical Materials
    - Government Documents, 1908, 1909, 1932-1939,1958 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      Rhys Passport (1939 and 1958), Rhys and Johannes Steel Marriage Certificate (1935), Rhys Marriage Announcement (1935), Rhys Certificate of Literacy (1932), Transcript of Register of Births (1937) with note (1937)
    - Academic Identification, 1929-1930, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Unidentified photographs and slide., 1902, 1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Sketch of Rhys by William Sharp (copy), undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence from Rhys to Harold, March 7, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Correspondence - Kenneth C. Royall, Rhys and Fredrick A. Colwell., 1953, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 71)
      Letters regarding Rhys. Kenneth C. Royall biography (copy)
    - Correspondence to Rhys from G.L. Caparn, October 3, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence from Friends, 1972, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Letters to Oliver Chamberlain, 1980, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Brief essay by Oliver Chamberlain on Rhys for Brearley School Alumnae Recognition and Exhibit, undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - "The Colours of Memory", undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
      Poems from 1955. From personal library.
    - Listing of works, 1955-1983 (Box 1, Folder 75)
      Original. Rhys. Drawing by Rhys on reverse.
    - Biographical Materials (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Exhibition Catalogs
    - Catalog - Spring Salon Catalog, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - 4th Annual Membership Exhibition, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 77)
      American Artists Congress.
    - 1941 Annual Exhibition of Sculpture, Watercolors, Drawings and Prints, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 77)
      Whitney Museum of American Art.
    - 50th-53rd Annual Exhibition: National Association of Women Artists, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 78)
      American Fine Arts Galleries
    - Collection. New York Six, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 79)
      by Petit Palais. Sculpture (French)
    - Sixty-second annual exhibition, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 79)
      University of Nebraska. Nebraska Art Association.
    - Caparn Selections from Thirty Years - Sculpture and Drawings, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - The Sculptors Guild: Sculpture 1948. Tenth Anniversary Outdoor Sculpture Exhibition., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - The Sculptors Guild: Sculpture 1953, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - The Sculptors Guild: Sculpture 1965, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Sculpture 1966, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 80)
      The Sculptors Guild.
    - The Sculptors Guild: Sculpture '68 (1968), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - The Alfred Khouri Memorial Collection, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Rhys Caparn Sculpture and Drawings, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Rhys Caparn. Retrospective exhibition sculpture and drawings, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 81)
      Bethel Gallery; hand written pricing.
    - Rhys Caparn, 1977, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 81)
      Washington Art Gallery (Invitation); hand written pricing.
    - Caparn at 75. Selected sculptures, pastels and drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
      Brief biography on back.
  - Printed Materials
    - Reviews - "Escape to the Present", 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
      Original. Johannes Steel. New York Times review of "Escape to the Present" (August 8, 1937), The Saturday Review of Literature: Reviews of "Escape to the Present" (July 24, 1937), Business Card, Johannes Steel on Wall Street; Price List of Rhys's sculptures, Obituatry (printed copy)
    - Fairfield County and American Artist Magazines, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      Regarding Ryhs' exhibition "The Years of Fulfillment"
    - Rhys Caparn. The Years of Fulfillment, October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      ARTnews. Art Magazine
    - The Sunday Post Article - "Newtowner's sculpture in Brooklyn", undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Article in "Outlook" titled "Three Connecticut Abstractionists", November 1981 (Box 1, Folder 84)
      Stamford Museum & Nature Center.
    - "The Newtown Bee", 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 85)
      Three newspaper articles.
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden Report, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 86)
      Rhys donates "Moonrise" to the Brooklyn Botanic Garden in memory of H.A. Caparn. Business card of Donald E. Moore (former president of Brooklyn Botanic Garden) is attached. Handwritten note on card. Photocopy of photo used in magazine.
    - Slides of Rhys Caparn's Work (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Series III. Other Caparn Family Members
  - William H. Caparn
    - Photograph - William H. Caparn, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Grandfather of H.A. Caparn. Photographed by S. Frost. Kirkgate Newark. Chamberlain Collection.
    - Photograph - William H. Caparn and Family, c. 1857 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      With Jane Smith, Mary Ann, Sarah Horner, Thomas John, George Miller, Robert, Daniel, John Smith, Rebecca Elizabeth and Georgina Miller. Names handwritten on reverse. Thomas John Caparn. Oliver Chamberlain. Notes on George Morland Paintings. Transcription of Thomas John Caparn's note. Bill.
    - Photograph - William H. Caparn and 11 children., undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Photocopy. ID of family members L-R in photograph.
    - Biography - "Furthering the History of the Family Caparn", undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Photocopy.
  - Thomas John Caparn
    - Correspondence - Invoice for two watercolors by George Morland, undated, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Barbis Fine Art Conservation LLC. "Two Figures with Donkey by George Morland" and "Laundry" by George Morland. Mold Treatment, Remove one from paper mount, light wash to reduce surface soiles, deacidified, retouched surace scratches and repaired tear.
    - Photograph - Thomas John Caparn, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Original. Thomas John Caparn. 2 photocopies. Photo by M.L. Green. Summit, NJ
    - Photography - Thomas John Caparn, c. 1910 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Photocopy. Thomas John Caparn. Print from original negative. Chamberlain Collection.
    - Book - "Drawing Book", 1853 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Thomas John Caparn. His drawing book as youth. Age 19. Signed.
    - 2 Advertisements for Thomas Caparn (and Arthur), 1886 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Copies
  - Mary and Ann Elizabeth (Price) Caparn
    - Correspondence - Letter to H.A. Caparn from his cousin Mary Caparn, July 15, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Original. Harold A. Caparn. Mary Caparn. Envelope from Harold to his brother, with note to return.
    - Correspondence - 80th Birthday Invitation, 1833, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Original. Ann Elizabeth Price Caparn. 3 photos include 1910, 1833 watercolor and photocopy. Original covers and uniform.
    - Newspaper - Clippings "Artist's Tramcar", "Passing of Blind Artists" and "Cremation of Mr. W. Caparne", October 1923, August 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Photocopy. Letter from Mary Caparn (cousin) to Harold Caparn). 144 E 30th, N.Y., then to Arthur T. Carparn. Short Hills.
  - Arthur Caparn
    - Photograph - Arthur T. Caparn, August 1893 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Original. On cardboard. Photograph includes J Voigt, A. T. Caparn, H. Merkle and J. McDonald on box. Pitcher and Manda Nurserymen. Seedsmen and Florists.
    - Book - "The Caparn Family of Newark & Some of Their Descendants" by G. Hemingway, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Photocopy. The Caparn Family. Hemingway's Notes and Queries
    - Photographs - Harold and Arthur Together, c. 1920, c. 1925 (Box 1, Folder 55;)
      Photocopy. Harold A. Caparn, Arthur T. Caparn, Emily A. Caparn, Kathleen E. Caparn and young girl. 2 photographs.
  - Oliver Chamberlain Jr.
    - Postcards - Collection of Oliver Chamberlain, 1908-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Regarding Landscape work and writings of H.A. Postcards include images of the Palisades Interstate Park, J.B. Pound residency, Orange Park, New York World's Fair Music Hall, Briarcliff Mansion, Residence of Webb Horton, Jackson Lake, Mt McGregor State Veterans Rehabilitation Center, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company Sanatorium Administration Building, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company Sanatorium Infirmary, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company Sanatorium John Rogers Memorial Laboratory, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company Sanatorium Rest House Across Artist Lake, J.B Pound Hotels, The Palisades on the Hudson, Park Road, Bear Mountain New York.
    - Postcards - Collection of Oliver Chamberlain, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 12)